Inauguration 2009 Sermons and Orations Project collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
Guides to the Collections in the Archive of Folk Culture
Inauguration 2009 Sermons and Orations Project Collection 2008-2009
AFC 2009/001
American Folklife Center
4489 items.
412 sound files (mp3, wav, wma on 128 CD-Rs): digital, sound.
16 sound cassettes: analog.
211 photographs (jpg, doc): digital, color.
35 photographic prints: black and white, color; various sizes.
83 videodiscs (DVD-R): digital, sound, color; 4 3/4 in.
9 videocassettes (MiniDV, VHS, Hi-8): sound, color; various sizes.
3600 pages (7 boxes, 3 linear feet)
123 text files (pdf, doc, jpg, rtf, pub, ppt): digital.
Archive of Folk Culture, American Folklife Center Library of Congress, Washington, D.C. http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.home
The Inauguration 2009 Sermons and Orations Project collection includes manuscripts (letters, sermons, orations, church programs, etc.), audio and video recordings, photographs, and other graphic materials created by the public in response to the 2009 election and inauguration of President Barack Obama and collected by the American Folklife Center. Includes submissions from over 300 individuals, religious and secular organizations, from 39 states and the District of Columbia, and from Nairobi, Kenya and Salvador, Bahia, Brazil, recorded January 16-25, 2009.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and listed alphabetically therein.
People
King, Martin Luther, Jr., 1929-1968.; Obama, Barack--Inauguration, 2009.; Obama, Barack.
Organizations
African Methodist Episcopal Church--Sermons.; American Folklife Center, collector.; Apostolic Faith Churches of God--Sermons.; Archive of Folk Culture (Library of Congress); Catholic Church--Sermons.; Christian and Missionary Alliance--Sermons.; Christian Methodist Episcopal Church--Sermons.; Community of Christ--Sermons.; Episcopalian Church--Sermons.; Library of Congress.; Lutheran Church--Sermons.; United Church of Christ--Sermons.; Vedanta Society--Speeches.
Subjects
African American leadership.; African Americans--Social conditions.; Atheists--Speeches.; Baptists--Sermons.; Catholics--Sermons.; Christian Science--Sermons.; Christians--Sermons.; Congregationalists--Sermons.; Conservative Judaism--Sermons.; Coptic sermons.; Hindu sermons.; Holidays--United States.; Humanists--Speeches.; Inauguration Day.; Interdenominational cooperation.; Interfaith worship.; Islamic sermons.; Jewish sermons.; Jews--Sermons.; Martin Luther King, Jr., Day.; Mennonites--Sermons.; Methodists--Sermons.; Muslims--Sermons.; Occasional sermons.; Presbyterian Church--Sermons.; Presidents--United States--Election--2008--Sermons.; Presidents--United States--Inauguration.; Public worship.; Quakers--Sermons.; Race relations--United States--Religious aspects.; Race relations--United States.; Reading in public worship.; Reconstructionist Judaism--Sermons.; Reform Judaism--Sermons.; Religious gatherings.; Sermons, American--21st century.; Sermons, Spanish--United States.; Sermons--Brazil--Salvador.; Sermons--Kenya--Nairobi.; Sermons--United States.; Seventh-Day Adventists--Sermons.; Society of Friends--Sermons.; Speeches, addresses, etc.; Unitarian Universalists--Sermons.; Worship programs.
Places
United States--Race relations.
Form/Genre
Digital photographs--Color--2000-2010.; Manuscripts.; Orations.; Photographs.; Poems.; Programs.; Sermons.; Sound recordings.; Speeches.; Video recordings.
Administrative Information
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series, I. Administrative and II. Submissions. The materials in this collection were initially organized by the submitting organization and assigned a submission number. Due to the unique nature of each submission, this arrangement allowed various formats to be intellectually grouped, thereby retaining the original sense of the submission. Because of the unique preservation needs of individual formats, the collection was physically arranged by format (manuscript, audio recording, graphic images, moving images, and digital files) during processing of the collection and housed accordingly. This finding aid is arranged by submission number, grouping all items from each organization together. See also the index for an alphabetical list of submitting organizations.
Acquisition
Materials for this collection were solicited from the public by the American Folklife Center via press releases, articles, emails, listservs, interviews, letters, and/or phone calls. Collection materials were submitted directly to the American Folklife Center by the individual and/or organizational creator of the materials via email, fax, and/or mail service.
Related Material
Kamala Lane, “Library Plans to Collect Sermons for Inauguration,” ABC News/AP Washington, January 2, 2009.
“U.S. library to collect sermons for inauguration,” USA Today, On Politics blog, January 2009.
“Library plans to collect inauguration sermons,” USA Today, January 2, 2009, http://www.usatoday.com/news/politics/election2008/2009-01-02-sermons-inauguration_N.htm
“Library plans to collect inauguration sermons,” MSNBC, http://www.msnbc.msn.com/id/28471680/
Access and Restrictions
Collection is open for research; access restrictions for some recordings may apply. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at http://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact. All audio-visual materials for this collection are served in the reading room as digital files (not on CD-Rs or DVD-Rs). Manuscripts and photographs that were submitted as digital files have been printed out for access. For manuscripts and photographs submitted as a hard copies or prints, the originals are served.
Administrative History
In anticipation of the January 20, 2009, inauguration of President Barack Obama, the American Folklife Center solicited audio and video recordings of sermons and orations that commented on the 2009 inauguration. These materials, solicited from the public through the American Folklife Center website as well as various press releases and other forms of communication, now form the Inauguration 2009 Sermons and Orations Project collection. The American Folklife Center requested that recordings must be of sermons and orations that were delivered to congregations and other audiences between Friday, January 16 and Sunday, January 25, 2009. In addition to audio and video recordings, the Center also requested written texts of sermons and orations (submitted in the form of print or electronic media), as well as printed programs from the events during which the sermons and orations were delivered. When materials were damaged during delivery to the American Folklife Center, replacement materials were requested. Participants were required to submit both an information form and a release form with their collection materials.
Scope and Content
The Inauguration 2009 Sermons and Orations Project collection consists of submissions by over 300 individuals, religious and secular organizations, and cultural groups documenting programs and celebrations of Barack Obama's presidential inauguration. These events occurred across the United States and in Nairobi, Kenya and Salvador, Bahia, Brazil. Each participant determined the nature of the materials submitted, resulting in a diverse collection of materials that includes, but is not limited to, the following: digital documents and files (including text-based documents, audio recordings, PowerPoint presentations, and image files); audio recordings (primarily audio cassettes and CD-R); video recordings (Hi-8, VHS, and DVD-R); manuscripts; and photographs (including physical and digital files). The specific topics and formats of each submission are unique, ranging from public speeches in varying formats (both religious and secular in nature), to creative writings and performances. In addition to the topic of the inauguration, many submissions referenced or discussed the birthday of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., which occurred Monday, January 19, 2009, the day before the inauguration. Included in this collection is a recording of the sermon that President and Mrs. Obama attended on January 18, 2009, at Nineteenth Street Baptist Church (Washington, D.C.) [Submission 0141]; as well as a video of the January 18, 2009, service from Ebenezer Baptist Church (Atlanta, Ga.) [Submission 0290], where Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., served as pastor. In addition, this collection includes submissions from the Washington National Cathedral (Washington, D.C.) [Submission 0295], as well as the Harvard University Memorial Church (Cambridge, Mass.) [Submission 0104] and the Yale University Divinity School [Submission 0143]. This collection also includes submissions from a variety of cultural and religious groups, including: atheists, Christians, Hindus, Humanists, Jews, Muslims, Quakers, and secular groups and organizations. See the index for an alphabetical list of people and organization names.
http://lccn.loc.gov/2013655317
Container List
- Administrative, 2008-2009
  - Finding aid (Box-folder 1/1)
  - Articles and press releases, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Submissions, 2008-2009
  - Iman, USA
    - Public Speech (Khutbah), 2009-01-09, 1 digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0001_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Roger Harned
    - The Lincoln Bible_1, 2009-01-19, 1 digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0002_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Congregation Beth Shalom (Napa, California)
    - Obama and the Midwives, Parashat Shemot, Exodus 5769, 2009-01-16, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0003_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Clarendon Presbyterian Church (Clarendon, Virginia)
    - Inaugurating Hope, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0004_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/6)
  - St. Francis' Episcopal Church (Dunellen, New Jersey)
    - A Sermon for the Sunday of Epiphany, Year B, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0005_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Nehar Shalom Community Synagogue (Jamaica Plain, Massachusetts)
    - Prayer for America, 1 digital pdf file and printed copy; afc2009001_0006_ms01.pdf (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Christ Church Community (Plumsteadville, Pennsylvania)
    - Letter to the President, 2009-01-20, 1 digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0007_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Program, 2009-01-18, 1 digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0007_ms02.doc (Box-folder 1/9)
  - Westmoreland Congregational Church (Bethesda, Maryland)
    - An Open Letter to a New President, 2009-01-18, 1 digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0008_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/10)
  - St. Mark's Church (Washington, D. C.)
    - 42:1-4, a reading from James Carse's The Beloved Disciple, Mk,1:7-12, 2009-01-18, 1 digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0009_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Harvest Church (Elk Grove, California)
    - The Dream that Came True, 2009-01-17, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0010_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/12)
  - Emmanuel Bible Church (Frederick, Maryland)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - In God We Trust, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/13)
    - In God We Trust, 2009-01-18, 1 sound recording: digital wav file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0011_sr01 (Box 11)
  - First Christian Church of Turlock (Turlock, California)
    - a conversation with angel Dr. Martin Luther King Jr...on Barack Obama, sitz inm le ben, and exegesis of zeitgeist, 2009-06-20, 2 copies (1 draft) (Box-folder 1/14)
    - a conversation with angel Dr. Martin Luther King Jr...on Barack Obama, sitz inm le ben, and exegesis of zeitgeist, 2009-01-06, 3 sound recordings: digital wav files; afc2009001_0012_sr01-sr03.wav
  - Dallas Christian College (Dallas, Texas)
    - Sermon, 2009-01-15, 1 sound recording: digital wma file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0013_sr01 (Box 11)
  - Abyssinia Baptist Church (Savannah, Georgia)
    - What Shall We Tell the Children- On the Inaugural of America's 44th President, Barrack Hussein Obama, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Program, 2009-01-18, 1 digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0014_ms02.doc (Box-folder 1/15)
    - Photographs of service, 2009-01-18, 67 photographs: digital, jpg, color and printed copies.; afc2009001_0014_ph01-ph67.jpg (Box-folder 1/15)
    - What Shall We Tell the Children- On the Inaugural of America's 44th President, Barrack Hussein Obama, 2009-01-18, 1 sound recording: digital wav file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0014_sr01 (Box 11)
  - St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Bailey's Crossroads, Virginia)
    - The Second Sunday Epiphany in Celebration of the Inauguration of Barack Obama and the Anniversary of the birthday of The Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - The Second Sunday Epiphany in Celebration of the Inauguration of Barack Obama and the Anniversary of the birthday of The Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., 2009-01-18, 1 sound recording: audio cassette tape; afc2009001_0015_sr01
    - The Second Sunday Epiphany in Celebration of the Inauguration of Barack Obama and the Anniversary of the birthday of The Rev. Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., 2009-01-18, 1 video recording: digital file submitted on DVD; afc2009001_0015_mv01 (Box 8)
  - Agudas Achim Congregation (Alexandria, Virginia)
    - Inauguration Weekend 2009, 2009-01-17, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Durga Temple (Fairfax Station, Virginia)
    - Speech, 2009-01-18, 1 digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0017_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Group at Hindu Temple, 2009-01-20, 1 photograph: digital, color, jpg file; afc2009001_0017_ph01.jpg
  - Morningside Presbyterian Church (Atlanta, Georgia)
    - Purple Mountains Majesties, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon: digital pdf file and printed copy; afc2009001_0018_ms01.pdf (Box-folder 1/19)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Temple Beth Am (Margate, Florida)
    - Sermon Shemot - The Inauguration - Synchronicity, 2009-01-17, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0019_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Machar: The Washington Congregation for Secular Humanistic Judaism (Washington, D.C.)
    - President Obama's Inaugural Call to Responsibility: All Hearts and Hands Needed, 2009-01-23, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0020_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/21)
  - First Parish Church (Ashby, Massachusetts)
    - The Challenge of Hope, 2009-01-25, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0021_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/22)
    - Program, 2009-01-25, 2 copies (Box-folder 1/22)
    - The Challenge of Hope, 2009-01-25, 1 sound recording: digital wav file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0021_sr01 (Box 11)
  - All Souls Unitarian Universalist Congregation (New London, Connecticut)
    - Are We Post-Racial? 2009-01-25, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0022_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/23)
  - Unitarian Universalist Meeting of South Berkshire (Great Barrington, Massachusetts)
    - Calling out the Dream, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/24)
  - St. John A. M. E. Zion Church (Odenton, Maryland)
    - Transforming Dreams, 2009-01-25, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/25)
    - Transforming Dreams, 2009-01-25, 1 sound recording: digital wav file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0025_sr01 (Box 11)
  - Ward African Methodist Episcopal Church (Los Angeles, California)
    - Providential Prayers for Presidential Leadership, 2009-01-25, 1 sermon (2 copies) (Box-folder 1/26)
  - Jewish Community Center of Harrison (Harrison, New York)
    - Oaths of Faith, 2009-01-24, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/27)
  - First Parish Church, Unitarian Universalist (Fitchburg, Massachusetts)
    - Dirty Hands and Moving Feet, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/28)
  - Beulah Baptist Church (Atlanta, Georgia)
    - Sermon, 2009-01-18, 3 sound recordings: digital wav files submitted on CD; afc2009001_0029_sr01-sr03 (Box 11)
  - Muri Giurgevich (Lexington, Kentucky)
    - Dr. MLKing, Jr. Birthday Card, 2009-01-10 (Box-folder 1/29)
  - Temple Beth Sholom (Miami Beach, Florida)
    - Sermon, 2009-01-16, 1 sound recording: audio cassette tape; afc2009001_0031_sr01
    - Sermon, 2009-01-16, 1 video recording: digital file submitted on DVD; afc2009001_0031_mv01 (Box 8)
  - Wyben Union Church (Westfield, Massachusetts)
    - The Content of Peace in the Heart Propels Goodwill Towards All People, 2009-01-19, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/30)
    - Portrait of Dr. Paine, 2009-01-19, 1 photographic print: black and white, 4 x 3 in. (Box-folder 1/30)
  - Channing Memorial Church (Ellicott City, Maryland)
    - A Clearer Vision, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/31)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/31)
    - A Clearer Vision, 2009-01-18, 1 video recording: digital file submitted on DVD; afc2009001_0033_mv01 (Box 8)
  - Little River United Church of Christ (Annandale, Virginia)
    - A New Day for Race in America, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0034_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/32)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/32)
    - A New Day for Race in America, 2009-01-18, 13 sound recordings: digital wav, aiff and mp3 files submitted on 2 CDs; afc2009001_0034_sr01-sr13 (Box 11)
  - Washington Area Secular Humanists, Inc. (Washington, D.C.)
    - On the Inauguration of Barack Obama to the Office of President of the United States, 2009-01-17, 1 speech: digital pdf and doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0035_ms01.pdf (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Oration Project attendees list (Box-folder 1/33)
    - Photographs of service, 2009-01-17, 4 photographs: digital, jpg, color and printed copies.; afc2009001_0035_ph01-ph04.jpg (Box-folder 1/33)
    - On the Inauguration of Barack Obama to the Office of President of the United States, 2009-01-17, 1 sound recording: digital mp3 file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0035_sr01 (Box 11)
    - On the Inauguration of Barack Obama to the Office of President of the United States, 2009-01-17, 1 video recording: digital file submitted on DVD; afc2009001_0035_mv01 (Box 8)
  - Trinity Church (Boston, Massachusetts)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. Sunday Sermon, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon: digital pdf file and printed copy; afc2009001_0036_ms01.pdf (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Program, 2009-01-18, 1 digital pdf file and printed copy; afc2009001_0036_ms02.pdf (Box-folder 1/34)
    - Martin Luther King Jr. Sunday Sermon, 2009-01-18, 1 sound recording: digital mp3 file; afc2009001_0036_sr01.mp3
  - Bow Mills United Methodist Church (Bow, New Hampshire)
    - Inauguration Day/ Martin Luther King Jr. Day Sermon, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0037_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/35)
    - Program, 2009-01-18, 1 digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0037_ms02.doc (Box-folder 1/35)
  - Christ Episcopal Church (East Orange, New Jersey)
    - Sermon, 2009-01-21 (Box-folder 1/36)
    - Sermon (On the inauguration of President Barack Obama), 2009-01-21 (Box-folder 1/36)
  - World Peace Prayer Society (Wasaic, New York)
    - Global Link Teleconference speeches, 2009-01-20, 2 speeches (Box-folder 1/37)
    - Global Link Teleconference posters, 2009-01-20, 2 posters (Box-folder 1/37)
  - St. John's Episcopal Church (Hempstead, New York)
    - Prayer for President Barack Obama, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/38)
  - Noble Road Presbyterian Church (Cleveland Heights, Ohio)
    - Spirit-Led Choices, 2009-01-25, 1 sermon: digital pdf file and printed copy; afc2009001_0041_ms01.pdf (Box-folder 1/39)
    - Program, 2009-01-25, 1 digital pdf file and printed copy; afc2009001_0041_ms02.pdf (Box-folder 1/39)
  - Harbor Unitarian Universalist Congregation (Muskegon, Michigan)
    - The Color of God, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon: digital doc file and printed copy; afc2009001_0042_ms01.doc (Box-folder 1/40)
  - New Mount Olive Baptist Church (Fort Lauderdale, Florida)
    - Moses and Obama, 2009-01-18, 1 video recording: digital file submitted on DVD; afc2009001_0043_mv01 (Box 8)
    - Obama: For Such a Time as This, 2008-11-16, 1 video recording: digital file submitted on DVD; afc2009001_0043_mv02 (Box 8)
    - After-After-After Now Change has Come to America, 1 video recording: digital file submitted on DVD; afc2009001_0043_mv03 (Box 8)
  - Valley Outreach Synagogue (Las Vegas, Nevada)
    - Envisioning Hope, Peace, Prosperity: The Inauguration of President Barack Obama, 2009-01-16, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/41)
  - Golden Valley United Methodist Church (Bostic, North Carolina)
    - About Moses, who saw the face of God, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/42)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/42)
  - Campbell Chapel African Methodist Episcopal Church (Virginia Beach, Virginia)
    - Dream Come True, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/43)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/43)
    - Seniors Bible Study flyer, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/43)
  - Western Presbyterian Church (Washington, D.C.)
    - The Spoils of Injustice, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/44)
  - Sun City Jewish Congregation (Palm City, California)
    - Some Unsolicited Advice for our New President, 2009-01-16, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/45)
    - Some Unsolicited Advice for our New President, 2009-01-16, 1 sound recording: audio cassette tape; afc2009001_0048_sr01
  - Columbia Falls United Methodist Church (Columbia Falls, Montana)
    - Unity; Not Homogenization, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 1/46)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 1/46)
    - Unity; Not Homogenization, 2009-01-18, 2 sound recordings: digital wav files submitted on CD; afc2009001_0049_sr01-sr02 (Box 11)
  - All Saints Episcopal Church (Salt Lake City, Utah)
    - Sermon, 2009-01-18, 1 sound recording: digital wav file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0050_sr01 (Box 11)
  - St. James United Church of Christ (Limerick, Pennsylvania)
    - Building Blocks of Hope, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 2/47)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 2/47)
  - Lockport United Church of Christ (Lockport, New York)
    - Many Hands, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 2/48)
  - The Ministry of UNI United News and Information (Pasadena, California)
    - Focus on Issues: A Look at News, Views and Trends (Program Notes - 753), 1 program (Box-folder 7/257)
    - Focus on Issues interview, 1 sound recording: digital wav file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0053_sr01 (Box 11)
  - St. Mark Presbyterian Church (Portland, Oregon)
    - Waited on by Angels, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 2/49)
  - Original Providence Baptist Church (Chicago, Illinois)
    - A Good Work, 2009-01-25, 1 sermon (Box-folder 2/50)
    - Program, 2009-01-25 (Box-folder 2/50)
  - Trinity Presbyterian Church (San Jose, California)
    - Transitions, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 2/51)
    - Program, 2009-01-18 (Box-folder 2/51)
    - Transitions, 2009-01-18, 1 sound recording: digital wav file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0056_sr01 (Box 11)
  - Unitarian Universalist Church of Delaware County (Media, Pennsylvania)
    - Dear America: A Letter to Our Nation, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon (Box-folder 2/52)
    - Dear America: A Letter to Our Nation, 2009-01-18, 1 sound recording: digital wav file submitted on CD; afc2009001_0057_sr01 (Box 11)
  - Beth Israel Synagogue (Latrobe, Pennsylvania)
    - Inauguration 2009, 2009-01-23, 1 sermon (Box-folder 2/53)
    - Inauguration 2009, 2009-01-23, 1 video recording: digital file submitted on DVD; afc2009001_0058_mv01 (Box 8)
  - Zion "Goshert's" United Church of Christ (Lebanon, Pennsylvania)
    - Miracle Boot Camp, 2009-01-18, 1 sermon: digital pdf file and printed copy; afc2009001_0059_ms01.pdf (Box-folder 2/54)
    - Lincoln's Second Inaugural Address, 1 speech (Box-folder 2/54)